Guide to the Sylvester Manor Archive 1649-1996 MSS.208
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Record Group IV: Horsford Family
  - Series A: Eben Norton Horsford
    - Subseries 1: Correspondence
      - Subsubseries a: Academic and Family
        - van den Wyngaert, Joseph: Berlin, Germany, 1875 January 3 - 1890 September 1; cuid2590 (Box 69, Folder 67)
          Addressed To: “Professor [Eben] N. [Norton] Horsford, Esq., Cambridge, MA,” “St. James Hotel, Corner of Broadway & 26th Street, New York, NY, U.S. of America”
          Sent From: “Jos. [Joseph] van den Wyngaert, Chairman of the Association of German Muller & Muhlen Prospects, Berlin,” [Germany]
          47 Pages, Bound & Unbound
          Measurements: 3.75” x 2.5” - 8.75” x 11”
        - van Rensselaer, W. Bayard: Wareham, MA, 1889 September 25; cuid2591 (Box 69, Folder 68)
          Sent From: “W. Bayard Van Rensselaer”
        - van Vradenburg, PD: Binghamton, NY, 1890 January 2; cuid2592 (Box 69, Folder 69)
          Sent From: “P.D. Van Vradenburg”
        - Vaughn, William J: Nashville, TN, 1889 July 12; cuid2593 (Box 69, Folder 70)
          Sent From: “Librarian William J. Vaughn, Vanderbilt Library, Nashville, TN”
        - [Vegnaur], Henry: Paris, France, 1889 September 4; cuid2594 (Box 69, Folder 71)
          Addressed To: “Mr. Eben [Norton] Horsford, ℅ John Wilson & Son, Cambridge,” [MA]
          Sent From: “Henry [Vegnaur], Legation of the United States of America, 59 rue Galilee, Paris,” [France]
        - von Hofmann, August Wilhelm: London, England, 1846 April 26; cuid2595 (Box 69, Folder 72)
          Sent From: “A.W. [August Wilhelm von] Hofmann, Ph.D, Professor of Chemistry, William University at Bonn, [Germany] and Professor at The Royal College of Chemistry, London, Honorary Member of The Royal Agricultural Society of England, 16 Hanover Square, London,” [England]
          In Reference To: Academic / Business / Education / Professional / Science; Harvard University
          August Wilhelm von Hofmann (April 8, 1818 – May 5, 1892) was a German chemist. After studying under Justus von Liebig at the University of Giessen, Hofmann became the first director of the Royal College of Chemistry in London in 1845. In 1865, Hofmann returned to Germany to accept a position at the University of Berlin as a teacher and researcher; he also co-founded the German Chemical Society (Deutsche Chemische Gesellschaft) in 1867. In both London and Berlin, Hofmann recreated the style of laboratory instruction established by Liebig at Giessen, fostering a school of chemistry focused on experimental organic chemistry and its industrial applications. Hofmann archival material is preserved at the Imperial College Archives in London, England.
        - von Liebig, Baron Justus Freiherr: Munich, Germany, 1868 July 20 - 1888 December 26; undated, circa 1870s - 1880s; cuid2596 (Box 69, Folder 73)
          6 Letters, 5 Envelopes with Indentation, Notation & Postage, 1 Picture Postcard with Ephemera
          Addressed To: “E.N. [Eben Norton] Horsford, Esq., Rumford Professor of Harvard University, Cambridge, MA, North America”
          Sent From: “[Baron] J. [Justus Freiherr von] Liebig, President of the Bavarian Academy of Sciences, München [Munich], Germany”; [Georg von Liebig]
          In Reference To: Academic / Business / Chemistry / Education / Food / Friendship / History / Personal / Professional / Science / Social; 1 Advertisement / Circular, “Extract From A Letter Of Baron Liebig, of Germany, To Professor Horsford,” [12 Copies]; Correspondence in English & German Language; “The Problem of the Northmen”; Correspondence dated after Liebig’s death, possibly from Liebig relative or Marie von Liebig
          Measurements: 4.5” x 3” - 7” x 8.5”
          Baron Justus Freiherr von Liebig (May 12, 1803 – April 18, 1873) was a German chemist. Liebig made significant contributions to agricultural and biological chemistry, and is considered to be the founder of organic chemistry. Liebig’s works are available at New York University Libraries via Bobcat.
        - von Liebig, Marie: Berchtesgaden, Germany, 1886 March 30 - 1888 November 16; undated, circa 1880s; cuid2597 (Box 69, Folder 74)
          4 Letters, 1 Picture Postcard
          Sent From: “Marie von Liebig, Berchtesgaden, Brandhuber Lehen,” [Germany]
          In Reference To: Friendship / Personal / Science / Social / Travel
          Measurements: 5.75” x 4.5” - 5.5” x 8.75”
        - von Littrow, Heinrich: Fiume, Croatia, 1873 August 21; cuid2598 (Box 69, Folder 75)
          Addressed To: “Honorable Professor [Eben Norton] Horsford”
          Sent From: “H. [Heinrich von] Littrow, k.k. Fregatten-Captaine, k. See-Inspector [Frigate Captain], Fiume,” [Currently Croatia & since the end of WWII, known as Rijeka]
          Measurements: 3.75” x 2.75” - 5.75” x 9”
          Heinrich von Littrow (January 26, 1820 – April 25, 1895) was an Austrian cartographer and writer. Littrow’s work is available at the German National Library in Frankfurt, Germany.
        - Vorman, Mary C: Auburndale, MA, 1889 July 19; cuid2599 (Box 69, Folder 76)
          Sent From: “Mary C. Vorman”
          In Reference To: Friendship / Personal / Social / Travel; Brooklyn, NY, Mr. Pratt
        - Waite, CC: Cincinnati, OH, 1889 February 15; cuid2600 (Box 69, Folder 77)
          1 Subscription Form with Notation
          Addressed To: [C.C. Waite]; [Eben Norton Horsford]
          Sent From: “Chairman C.C. Waite, Alumni Building, Endowment Fund, Cincinnati, OH”; “E.N. Horsford”
        - Waite, Morrison Remick: Boston, MA, 1887 January 14; cuid2601 (Box 69, Folder 78)
          Sent From: “President National Advisory Board, Honorable M.R. / Morrison Remick Waite, L.L.D., Chief Justice Supreme Court, U.S.A., American Institute of Civics, President’s Office, Phillips Building, Hamilton Place, Boston, MA”
        - Walker, John S: New York & Vermont, 1840 October 5 - 1842 October 8; 1890 February 6; cuid2602 (Box 69, Folder 79)
          Addressed To: “E.N. [Eben Norton] Horsford, Esq., ℅ Mr. C.E. Little, Albany, NY”
          Sent From: “J.S. Walker, Aurora, Cayuga County / Lockport / Tattler Office, Buffalo, NY,” with “J.S. Walker, Jr. The Windsor National Bank, No. 3257, Windsor, VT”
        - Walker, WF: Troy, NY, 1840 May 13; cuid2603 (Box 69, Folder 80)
          Addressed To: “Mr. [Eben Norton] Horsford, Civil Engineer, Albany, NY”
          Sent From: “W.F. Walker”
        - Wall, William E: Somerville, MA, 1889 November 25; cuid2604 (Box 69, Folder 81)
          Sent From: “William E. Wall, Grainer, Morgan Street, Somerville, MA”
        - Wallace, FT: Cleveland, OH, 1890 January 30 & February 10; cuid2605 (Box 69, Folder 82)
          Sent From: “F.T. Wallace, 49 Rockwell Street, Cleveland, OH”
          In Reference To: Academic / Business / Education / History / Professional; Boston, MA, Charles River, “The Discovery of the Ancient City of Norumbega”
        - Walmsley, Alice & Henry: Eau Claire, WI, 1884 July 30 & August 22; cuid2606 (Box 70, Folder 1)
          2 Announcements
          Sent From: “Alice Freeman Walmsley with Henry Durant Walmsley”
        - Waltham Public Library: Waltham, MA, 1889 July 25, August 29 & September 6; cuid2607 (Box 70, Folder 2)
          2 Letters, 2 United States Postal Cards with Postage
          Sent From: “Librarian Summer Johnson, Waltham Public Library,” [Waltham, MA]
          In Reference To: Academic / Business / Education / History / Professional; “Sketch for Tower at Norumbega”; “The Problem of the Northmen”
          Measurements: 5.25” x 3” - 5.75” x 9”
        - Ward, Henry Augustus: Rochester, NY, 1861 December 11 - 1883 March 31; cuid2608 (Box 70, Folder 3)
          Sent From: “Henry A. [Augustus] Ward, Rochester University / Ward’s Natural Science Establishment, No. 2 College Avenue (Opposite University), Rochester, NY”
          In Reference To: Academic / Business / Education / Professional; American Appreciation of Science; Lewis H. Morgan
          Measurements: 4.75” x 6” - 8.25” x 11”
          Henry Augustus Ward (1834 - 1906) was an American educator, geologist, and naturalist. The Henry Augustus Ward Papers (1840-1933) are preserved at the River Campus Library, University of Rochester in Rochester, NY.
        - Warfield, Ethelbert: Natick, MA, 1890 August 28; cuid2609 (Box 70, Folder 4)
          1 Announcement
          Sent From: “Mr. Ethelbert Dudley Warfield, Miss Nellie Frances Tilton, Natick, MA / Miami University, Oxford, OH”
          In Reference To: Family / Friendship / Personal / Social; Marriage Announcement
        - Warren, J: Boston, MA, 1888 December 22; [no year] January 31, circa 1890; cuid2610 (Box 70, Folder 5)
          Sent From: “J. Warren, 58 Beacon Street,” [Boston, MA]
        - Warren, Winslow: Boston, MA, 1892 May 23 & 31; cuid2611 (Box 70, Folder 6)
          Sent From: “Winslow Warren with Alfred S. Foster, Attorney And Counsellor At Law, 39 Court Street, Boston, MA”
          Measurements: 6” x 3.75” - 5.25” x 8”
        - Washburton, Charles: Stafford, NY, 1838 November 29; cuid2612 (Box 70, Folder 7)
          Sent From: “Charles Washburton”
        - Watertown Free Public Library: Watertown, MA, 1889 July 15 & September 3; cuid2613 (Box 70, Folder 8)
          Addressed To: "Professor Eben Norton Horsford, Cambridge / Lenox, MA"
          Sent From: "Librarian Solon F. Whitney, Watertown Free Public Library, Watertown, MA"
          In Reference To: Academic / Business / Education / History / Professional; "Sketch for Norse Tower"; "The Problem of the Northmen"
        - Watson, H: Albany, NY, 1839 December 19; cuid2614 (Box 70, Folder 9)
          Addressed To: [Eben Norton Horsford]; “Owner of the Shop,” [H. Watson]
          Sent From: “E.N. Horsford, Esq., No. 32 Commercial Buildings, Albany,” [NY]; “H. Watson”
        - Watson, Miss: [Cambridge, MA], undated, circa 1880s; cuid2615 (Box 70, Folder 10)
          Addressed To: “My dear Madam,” [Miss Watson, Unidentified Location, Possibly Cambridge, MA]
        - Watson, ML: Boston, MA, [no year] February 12, circa 1880s; cuid2616 (Box 70, Folder 11)
          Sent From: “M.L. Watson, 107 Marlborough Street,” [Boston, MA]
          Measurements: 4.25” x 5”
        - [Weathesheen, Daniel: Pondsville, NY], 1839 July 23; cuid2617 (Box 70, Folder 12)
          Addressed To: “Mr. E.N. [Eben Norton] Horsford, Esq., Moscow, Livingston County, NY”
          Sent From: [Daniel Weathesheen]
        - Weidenbusch, H: Wiesbaden, Germany, 1889 September 19; cuid2618 (Box 70, Folder 13)
          Sent From: “H. Weidenbusch, Wiesbaden, Deutsches Reich,” [Germany]
          In Reference To: Friendship / Personal / Social; In German Language
        - Welling, James C: Washington, D.C., 1888 September 23; cuid2619 (Box 70, Folder 14)
          Sent From: “James C. Welling,” [Possibly James Clarke Welling, (1825–1894), American educator, co-founder of National Geographic Society]
          In Reference To: Academic / Business / Eucation / History / Professional; “The Problem of the Northmen”
        - Wells, David Ames: Connecticut; New York; Rhode Island, 1886 September 7 - 1889 September 7; cuid2620 (Box 70, Folder 15)
          16 Letters, 1 Western Union Telegraph Form with Ephemera & Notation
          Addressed To: “My Dear Professor, Shelter Island, NY,” [Eben Norton Horsford]
          Sent From: “D.A. / David A. Wells, Esq. / Wells, Atlantic & West Indian Line, Leaycraft & Company, Managing Agents, 440 & 442 Pearl Street, P.O. Box 3455, New York,” [NY], “Hale & Company, Proprietors, Watch Hill House, Watch Hill, RI,” “Norwich, CT”
          In Reference To: Academic / Friendship / Education / Personal / Social / Travel; 1 Newsprint Clipping, “A Charming Winter Trip”; Wellesley College
          Measurements: 5” x 8” - 8” x 9.75”
          David Ames Wells (June 17, 1828 – November 5, 1898) was an American author, economist, and engineer. Wells archival material is preserved at the Albert and Shirley Small Special Collections Library at the University of Virginia in Charlottesville, VA, the Library of Congress in Washington, D.C., and the New York Public Library in New York, NY.
        - Wells, RH: [Albany, NY], 1843 May 14; cuid2621 (Box 70, Folder 16)
          Sent From: “J. [Jerediah] Horsford, Moscow,” [NY], [Father of Eben Norton Horsford]; “R.H. Wells,” [Unidentified Location, Possibly Albany, NY]
        - Western Union Telegraph Company: New York, NY, 1887 July 19 & September 16; cuid2622 (Box 70, Folder 17)
          Addressed To: “Professor E.N. [Eben Norton] Horsford, Sylvester Manor, Shelter Island, NY”; “The President of the Western Union Telegraph Company”
          Sent From: “E.N. Horsford”; “Superintendent Walter C. Humstone, Western Union Telegraph Company, Superintendent’s Office, 195 Broadway, New York,” [NY]
        - Wheeler, Horace Leslie: Newton, MA, 1890 January 15 - March 15; cuid2623 (Box 70, Folder 18)
          Sent From: “The Reverend Horace Leslie Wheeler, P.O. Box 222, Newton Centre, MA”
          In Reference To: Academic / Business / Education / History / Professional; “Charles River & the Northmen”; Mr. Rand; Norumbega
        - Wheildon, William Willder: Concord, MA, 1889 December 11; 1890 January 6; cuid2624 (Box 70, Folder 19)
          Sent From: “W.W. [William Willder] Wheildon”
          William Willder Wheildon (1805 - 1892) was an American historical and literary editor, journalist, lecturer, printer, publisher, and writer. The William Willder Wheildon Papers (1838-1889) are preserved at the Concord Free Public Library in Concord, MA.
        - Whipple, Charles: Bennington, VT, 1837 December 14; 1838 February 14 & May 7; cuid2625 (Box 70, Folder 20)
          Sent From: “Charles Whipple, Bennington, VT,” “Detroit, MI”
        - Whitaker, Epher: Southold, NY, 1884 July 15; 1886 January 16; 1887 October 4; 1889 August 27; cuid2626 (Box 70, Folder 21)
          Sent From: “Epher Whitaker”
          In Reference To: Academic / Business / Education / History / Professional; “John Cabot’s Landfall, The Sites of Norumbega”; Mr. Henry Lloyd, The Brooklyn Eagle; “The Problem of the Northmen”; Wellesley College
        - White, Horace: New York, NY, 1887 April 7 - July 22; 1889 May 21; cuid2627 (Box 70, Folder 22)
          4 Letters, 1 Western Union Telegraph Form with Notation
          Addressed To: “Professor E.N. [Eben Norton] Horsford, Cambridge, MA,” "Shelter Island, NY"
          Sent From: “Horace White, The Evening Post, Editorial Rooms, New York,” [NY]
          In Reference To: Academic / Business / Education / Friendship / History / Personal / Social / Travel; "Letter to Judge Daly / The Problem of the Northmen"; Mr. Wells; Shelter Island, Wellesley College
          Measurements: 8" x 5" - 5.25” x 8.5”
        - White, John Williams: Cambridge, MA, 1886-1887; cuid2628 (Box 70, Folder 23)
          Sent From: “John W. [Williams] White, 18 Concord Avenue, Cambridge,” [MA], "Archaeological Institute Of America, School Of Classical Studies At Athens”
        - White, Mr. & Mrs. JB: Moscow, NY, 1888 January 31; cuid2629 (Box 70, Folder 24)
          Sent From: “Mr. & Mrs. J.B. White”
        - Whitmore, Henry: Boston, MA, [no year] May 20, circa 1880s; cuid2630 (Box 70, Folder 25)
          Sent From: “Henry Whitmore,” [Possibly William Henry Whitmore, 1836-1900, Boston businessman, genealogist & politician]
          In Reference To: Academic / Business / Education / History / Professional; "The Problem of the Northmen," Norumbega
        - Whitney, Anne with John F: Boston, MA; Shelburne, NH, 1889 July 24 - September 21; [no year] May 5 - October 27, circa 1889; cuid2631 (Box 70, Folder 26)
          Sent From: “Anne Whitney, 92 Mt. Vernon Street, Boston,” [MA], “Shelburne, NH”; “Secretary John F. Whitney, The Historical Society of Watertown,” [MA]
          In Reference To: Academic / Business / Education / History / Professional; Leif Erikson [Ericson]; Norumbega
          Measurements: 4” x 6” - 6” x 9.25”
          Anne Whitney (September 2, 1821 – January 23, 1915) was an American sculptor and poet. The Anne Whitney Papers (1834-1915) are preserved at Wellesley College Archives in Wellesley, MA.
        - Whitney, Henry A: Boston, MA; Montreal, Canada, 1886 January 16; [no year] January 24 & June 9, circa 1880s; cuid2632 (Box 70, Folder 27)
          Sent From: “Henry A. Whitney, 17 Prince Arthur Street, Montreal,” [Canada], “54 Boylston Street / Young’s Hotel, Boston,” [MA]
          In Reference To: Academic / Business / Education / Native Americans / Professional; “Indian Names of Boston”
        - Whitney, WC: Washington, D.C., 1887 July 12 & 20; cuid2633 (Box 70, Folder 28)
          Addressed To: “Mr. H. Weld Fuller, Treasurer & General Agent of the Woodlawn Cemetery Company, Boston, MA”
          Sent From: “John W. Pettingill, Standing & Chief Justice of the First District Court of Eastern Middlesex, Malden, MA”; “W.C. Whitney, Secretary of the Navy, Navy Department, Washington, D.C.”
          In Reference To: Business / Legal / Professional; Lieutenant Colonel Broome
          Measurements: 8.25” x 13.25”
        - Whitney, WD: New Haven, CT, 1887 April 20; cuid2634 (Box 70, Folder 29)
          Sent From: “W.D. Whitney”
        - Whittier, JG: Amesbury, MA, 1884 January 24; cuid2635 (Box 70, Folder 30)
          2 Envelopes with Notation & Postage
          Sent From: “J.G. Whittier”
          Measurements: 5.5” x 3”
        - Wickham, William with Others: England; New York, 1873 July 14 & 19; 1874 July 19; 1887 July 9; 1889 March 12; cuid2636 (Box 70, Folder 31)
          5 Letters with Indentation, Notation & Postage, 1 Calling / Visiting Card
          Sent From: “William Wickham, Cutchogue, NY”; [Wickary, Lyme, NY]; [W.W., 22 Victoria Park, Dover,” [Kent, England]; "Mr. Williamson, University College, 15 Primrose Hill Road, NW," [London, England]
          Measurements: 3” x 1.5” - 7.5” x 12.5”
        - Wiesner, Julius: Rhine, Austria, 1874 May 12; cuid2637 (Box 70, Folder 32)
          Sent From: “Julius Wiesner, Rhine, III Ungargasse 63,” [Austria]
        - Will, Dr. H: Giessen, Germany, 1846 March 24; cuid2638 (Box 70, Folder 33)
          Sent From: “Dr. H. Will, Professor, University of Giessen,” [Germany]
        - William J. Wollman & Company: Kansas City, MO, 1890 May 12; cuid2639 (Box 70, Folder 34)
          Sent From: “William J. Wollman & Company, Bonds, Stocks, Commercial Paper, 516 Delaware Street, Kansas City, MO”
          Measurements: 8.5” x 7.25”
        - Williams, Annie H: Phenix, RI; Worcester, MA, 1889 July 29 & August 14; cuid2640 (Box 70, Folder 35)
          Sent From: “Annie H. Williams, [56 B. Street], Worcester, MA,” “Phenix, RI”
          In Reference To: Academic / Education / Friendship / Personal / Social / Travel; Wellesley College
        - Williams, Mr. & Mrs. Clarence H: Seneca Falls, NY, 1889 June 6; cuid2641 (Box 70, Folder 36)
          Sent From: “Mr. & Mrs. Clarence H. Williams, Trinity Church, Seneca Falls, NY”
          In Reference To: Family / Friendship / Personal / Social; 1 Invitation to Alice Tilton - Clayton Herbert Thorndike Wedding
        - Willis, Edward: Kingston, MA, 1889 April 26; cuid2642 (Box 70, Folder 37)
          Sent From: “Edward Willis”
        - Willson, Marcius: Vineland, NJ, 1889 July 10 & 13; cuid2643 (Box 70, Folder 38)
          Sent From: “Marcius Willson”
        - Wilson, AM: New Bedford, MA; Temple Hill, NY, 1834 February 7 - November 7; 1839 December 3; 1883 June 5; cuid2644 (Box 70, Folder 39)
          6 Letters, 1 Invitation with Notation
          Addressed To: “Mr. Eben [Norton] Horsford, ℅ J. [Jerediah] Horsford, Moscow,” [NY]
          Sent From: “A.M.W. / A.M. Willson / Mrs. Wilson / Mrs. Watson, New Bedford, MA / Temple Hill, Geneseo, NY”
          In Reference To: Friendship / Personal / Social / Religion; 1 Note with White Ribbon
          Measurements: 3.25” x 2” - 8” x 10”
        - Wilson, Daniel: Toronto, Canada, 1889 July 12; cuid2645 (Box 70, Folder 40)
          Addressed To: “E. [Eben] Norton Horsford, Esq.”
          Sent From: “Daniel Wilson, University College, Toronto,” [Canada]
        - Wilson, John: Cambridge, MA, 1886 August 6 - 1890 July 10; cuid2646 (Box 70, Folder 41)
          14 Letters, 3 United States Postal Card with Notation & Postage
          Addressed To: “E.N. [Eben Norton] Horsford, Sylvester Manor, Shelter Island, NY”; "J. Wilson & Son, Cambridge, MA"
          Sent From: "James Kelly, Bookseller & Importer, 26 Bond Street, NY"; “John Wilson & Son, Stereotypers, Electrotypers & Printers, University Press, Cambridge, MA”
          In Reference To: Academic / Business / Education / History / Financial / Native Americans / Professional; David Zeisberger’s Indian Dictionary; Library Festival; Miss Merrill; [Mr. J.N.N. MacNamee], “How I Came By A Berghem”; “John Cabot’s Landfall / Leif [Erikson / Ericson],” “The Problem of the Northmen”
        - Wiltse, HA with SC: New York State, 1836 December 1 - 1838 March 16; cuid2647 (Box 70, Folder 42)
          Addressed To: “E.N. Horsford, Esq., Assistant State Geologist, Albany, NY,” “Civil Engineer, Moscow, Livingston County / Rochester, NY”
          Sent From: “H.A. Wiltse, Ithaca / Speedville, NY,” with “S.C. Wiltse, Geneva, NY”
          In Reference To: Business / Friendship / Geology / Personal / Professional / Science / Social
          Measurements: 3.25” x 2.75” - 7.5” x 9.75”
        - Wing, Ada G: Marblehead & Palmer, MA, 1889 July 3 & 27; cuid2648 (Box 70, Folder 43)
          Sent From: “Ada G. Wing”
          In Reference To: Academic / Education / Friendship / History / Personal / Social; “The Problem of the Northmen,” Miss Peabody; Wellesley College
        - Winslow, William C: Boston, MA, 1887 June 11 - 1888 November 29; cuid2649 (Box 70, Folder 44)
          3 Letters, 1 United States Postal Card with Notation
          Addressed To: “Professor E.N. [Eben Norton], Horsford, L.L.D., Cambridge, MA”
          Sent From: “Vice President Reverend William C. Winslow, Egypt Exploration Fund, 429 / 525 Beacon Street, Boston,” [MA], “No. 3 West Cedar Street,” [Boston, MA]
          In Reference To: Academic / Business / Financial / Professional; Egyptological Exploration
        - Winsor, Constance & Justin: Cambridge, MA, 1886 May 12 & 26; 1887 November 1; 1889 February 8; undated, circa 1880s; cuid2650 (Box 70, Folder 45)
          21 Letters, 1 United States Postal Card with Postage
          Addressed To: “Mr. / Professor E.N. [Eben Norton] Horsford”; “Mr. Gilman”
          Sent From: “Constance Winsor, 74 Sparks Street, Cambridge,” [MA], [Daughter of Justin Winsor]; “Justin Winsor, 74 Sparks Street, Cambridge,” [MA], “Editor of Narrative & Critical History Of America, The Memorial History of Boston, Cambridge,” [MA], “Librarian Justin Winsor, The Corporation of Harvard College, Harvard College, Cambridge, MA / Harvard College Library, Gore Hall, Cambridge, MA”; “Mrs. Justin Winsor, [Caroline Tufts Barker]”
          In Reference To: Academic / Education / Friendship / History / Personal / Social; American Historical Association; “Champlain’s Voyages”; “Harriet, the Moses of Her People”; “How I Came By A Berghem by E.N.H. & Souvenir of Wellesley College, 1888”; Charles River; Houghton, Mifflin & Company; “The Problem of the Northmen / Letter to Judge Daly”; Wellesley College, Alice Elvira Freeman Palmer
          49 Pages, Bound & Unbound
          Justin Winsor (January 2, 1831 – October 22, 1897) was an American historian, librarian, and writer. Winsor’s historical work had strong bibliographical and cartographical elements; he was also an authority on the early history of North America. Winsor archival material is preserved at the Houghton Library at Harvard College in Cambridge, MA and the Massachusetts Historical Society in Boston, MA.